<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on XKZZZZZZ&#39;s Lab</title>
    <link>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on XKZZZZZZ&#39;s Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 23:40:03 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;20 Ranges at First Glance</title>
      <link>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/cpp20-ranges-at-first-glance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 23:40:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/cpp20-ranges-at-first-glance/</guid>
      <description>Since years before C++ 20&amp;rsquo;s release, I have been keeping a close eye on it. Many new features fairly tickle my fancy, among which are &amp;lt;ranges&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;format&amp;gt; library components. While there&amp;rsquo;s no available implementation for &amp;lt;format&amp;gt; yet, MSVC 16.8 and GCC-10 provides a usable &amp;lt;ranges&amp;gt; which I played with and writes the post for.
My life highly involved closely with programming begins with a long period using C#. Among all the language features of C#, LINQ is the beloved one for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Dionysus : The Vision of 2021</title>
      <link>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/project-dionysus-vision-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 23:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/project-dionysus-vision-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>Now, at the beginning of 2021, while celebrating the anniversary of this project, where most of my effort in the past year was devoted, it&amp;rsquo;s vital to make clear the road head for it.
Hindsight What has been done for it in the past year and a few months? Above growing from the very first assembly file to a large project with tens of thousands of lines of code, these aspects stands out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Dionysus - Why and What</title>
      <link>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/project-dionysus-why-and-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 16:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/project-dionysus-why-and-what/</guid>
      <description>Prologue  Dating back to a year ago, when I was attempting to add various features to the original rexv6-2 project, I am trapped by some very tough issues. I had been ambitious about the plan, but many of them turn out to be too hard to be carried out, and some of the original code of xv6, frankly speaking, is somehow out of date. That&amp;rsquo;s when it flashed on me that it may be better to build a new one from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Re-xv6-2 project</title>
      <link>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/announcing-rexv6-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 23:11:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/announcing-rexv6-proj/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Being considered as the three romances of a programmer, An OS is both challenging and interesting project to dive in. As a mature codebase of operation system study, xv6 is a good re-implementation of Unix v6, which is used by MIT&amp;rsquo;s 6.828. This project aims at apply improvements on the a quasi-original codebase of xv6 (xv6-improved) , adding including new kernel features and user support so as to create a linux-like full-featured kernel, including some modern techniques, such as MLFQ scheduling and an extended file system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respberry Pi 3B&#43; Headless Setup</title>
      <link>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/resp-pi-headless-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 19:40:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xkzzzzzz.xyz/posts/resp-pi-headless-setup/</guid>
      <description>Hands-On This morning I finally received my Raspberry Pi, after an eight-day-long delivery. Raspberry Pi 3B+, released in 2018, as is said, is more powerful than its predecessor. The first step after opening the box is to add two head sinks on the chip. The CPU doesn&amp;rsquo;t need one although its performance has been greatly improved, for it already has one. The given box has no reserved space for GPIO pins, which make it impossible to use it with GPIO peripherals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
